A Guide to the Near East Foundation records, Accession 2012:060, RG 5 FA1308
Rockefeller Archive Center
Near East Foundation records, Accession 2012:060, RG 5
1915-1997
Rockefeller Archive Center
Near East Foundation
Near East Relief (Organization)
FA1308
3.93 Cubic Feet 3 standard record storage boxes, Boxes 1-3
3 standard record storage boxes, Boxes 1-3.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research, with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items may be restricted at the discretion of the RAC.
Separated Materials
Special format items (audio, film, video, digital media, library materials, memorabilia, oversize, and photographic material) have been separated from the body of the collection and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
Arrangement
Arranged as received.
Scope and Contents
Primarily includes: "The Near East" (1920s), newsletters, other articles, as well as NEF Dockets, 1990-1997.
- Near East Foundation records, Accession 2012:060, 1915-1997; 5; 3.6 Cubic Feet
  - The New York Times, 1916 February 27 (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Brittle or damaged items may be restricted from access at the discretion of RAC.
  - The New York Times, 1915 October 4 (Box 1)
  - Loose Letters and Pamphlets (Box 1)
  - Report of Audit of Fund-Raising Program of The Near East Foundation (Box 1)
  - Fund-Raising Plan and Case Statement for the Near East Foundation, 1956 December (Box 1)
  - Fund-Raising Plan and Case Statement for the Near East Foundation BADEAU, 1956 December (Box 1)
  - Near East Foundation News (Box 1)
  - NEF Newsletters, 1964-1978 (Box 1)
  - Near East Foundation Albanian Area Reconnaissance Sanitary Survey of 12 Albanian Villages, 1934 April (Box 1)
  - Near East Foundation Manual of Regional Office Accounting, 1930 March 10 (Box 1)
  - Special Report of the Comptroller On the Financial Condition of Near East Relief, Near East Industries and Near East Foundation, 1933 October 31 (Box 1)
  - Near East Relief Near East Foundation Proposed Budget for the six months ending, 1931 June 30 (Box 1)
  - ALPHA Kermani, Rustam K. (Box 1)
  - Trial Balance* Africian Ledger D/O 's c-73-15, 1976 January 31-1977 June 30 (Box 1)
  - The Near East, 1924 January-June (Box 1)
  - The Near East, 1923 July-December (Box 1)
  - The Near East, 1923 January-June (Box 1)
  - The Near East, 1922 January-June (Box 2)
  - The Near East, 1924 July-December (Box 2)
  - The Near East, 1926 January-June (Box 2)
  - The Near East, 1925 July-December (Box 2)
  - The Near East, 1925 January-June (Box 2)
  - The Near East, 1922 July-December (Box 2)
  - The Near East (Box 2)
  - The Near East (Box 2)
  - Dockets, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Dockets, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Dockets, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Dockets, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Dockets, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Dockets, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Dockets, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Dockets, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Mail Appeals Historical Data Library, 1955-1956 (Box 3)
  - Mail Appeals Historical Data Library, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - Mail Appeals Historical Data Library, 1953-1954 (Box 3)
  - Mail Appeals Historical Data Library (Box 3)
  - Mail Appeals Historical Data Library (Box 3)
  - Mail Appeals Historical Data Library (Box 3)
  - Loose Material (Box 3)
  - Institute of Rural Life, 1936-1939 (Box 3)
  - Inactive File - Building Plans 54 East 64th Street (Box 3)
  - Inactive File - Building Sale to M. Sasayama, 1979 (Box 3)
  - "Judy in Constantinople" by Judy Acheson (Box 3)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Received as Accession 2013:021.
  - "Young America Looks at Russia" by Judy Acheson (Box 3)